const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"30-year-old Arshad came into the rehabilitation clinic as he uses cocaine and wants to quit. On assessment, he only needs the drug to satisfy his emotional and psychological needs but not getting the drug does not experience any withdrawal symptoms. What is he likely to have?","answers":[{"option":"Drug dependence","bool":false},{"option":"Habituation","bool":false},{"option":"Psychological dependence","bool":true},{"option":"Drug addiction","bool":false},{"option":"Physical dependence","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"30-year-old Ayesha came into the psychiatry department with complaints of sweating, headache, nausea, and cramping pain if she does not take heroin. What are the symptoms she is experiencing termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Drug habit","bool":false},{"option":"Habituation","bool":false},{"option":"Withdrawal symptoms","bool":true},{"option":"Tolerance","bool":false},{"option":"Drug dependence","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 15-year-old teenage boy came to the psychiatry department as he wants to stop taking heroin. On assessment, he reported that he needs to frequently increase the dose of the drug to have the same effect as before. What is the teenager said to have developed?","answers":[{"option":"Tolerance to heroin","bool":true},{"option":"Addiction to heroin","bool":false},{"option":"Experiencing withdrawal symptoms","bool":false},{"option":"Habituation to heroin","bool":false},{"option":"Craving of heroin","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 35-year-old woman presents to the medical outpatient department (OPD) for a regular checkup. On examination, her blood pressure is slightly elevated at 180/100 mmHg. She is physically fit and follows a healthy diet. The physician decided to start antihypertensive therapy and prescribe hydrochlorothiazide. What is the possible mechanism of action of hydrochlorothiazide?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibits reabsorption of sodium chloride by inhibiting the carbonic anhydrase enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits reabsorption of sodium chloride in the ascending limb of the loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits reabsorption of sodium and potassium excretion by inhibiting the aldosterone actions","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits reabsorption of sodium chloride in the distal convoluted tubule","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibits reabsorption of sodium chloride in the proximal tubule","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 55-year-old patient is admitted with a massive gastrointestinal (GI) bleed. The patient is at risk for what type of acute kidney injury?","answers":[{"option":"Pre-renal","bool":true},{"option":"Intra-renal","bool":false},{"option":"Intrinsic renal","bool":false},{"option":"Post-renal","bool":false},{"option":"Para-renal","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 62-year-old female complains of pain in her right flank. There is tenderness at the right costo-vertebral angle. Laboratory tests show microscopic hematuria but no protein or glucose. Complete blood count (CBC) shows microcytic and hypochromic anemia. Computed tomography (CT) scan reveals an irregular renal mass 5.2 cm in diameter occupying the upper pole of the right kidney. A biopsy is performed and histology shows atypical cells with pleomorphic nuclei and abundant clear cytoplasm. Molecular studies in this patient would most likely identify mutations in which of the following genes?","answers":[{"option":"IGF-2","bool":false},{"option":"Rb","bool":false},{"option":"VHL","bool":true},{"option":"p53","bool":false},{"option":"WT1","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A female rape victim is brought by police to the medico-legal section for examination. What is the first step you will take before starting the examination?","answers":[{"option":"Note personal data","bool":false},{"option":"Ask for authority letter","bool":true},{"option":"Ensure privacy","bool":false},{"option":"Note marks of identification","bool":false},{"option":"Take written consent of victim","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"According to the hudood ordinance, what is the punishment of Zina liable to Hudd when both male and female are muhsan?","answers":[{"option":"Five years imprisonment","bool":false},{"option":"10 years imprisonment","bool":false},{"option":"Hundreds strips","bool":false},{"option":"Stoned to death","bool":true},{"option":"Fine not exceeding ten thousand rupees","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A victim of sexual assault was brought by police to the medico-legal section for examination. On examination, the anal orifice was dilated and tender to touch, abrasions were present between the anus and tip of the coccyx. The victim was subjected to which of the following sexual offense?","answers":[{"option":"Sodomy","bool":true},{"option":"Tribadism","bool":false},{"option":"Sadism","bool":false},{"option":"Bestiality","bool":false},{"option":"Rape","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A dead body of a girl was brought for autopsy. On examination, she was pregnant, and severe injuries were observed in her pelvic area. On inquiry, her mother told that she tried to criminally induce abortion during which she died within minutes. What is the most probable cause of death?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Renal Failure","bool":false},{"option":"Septicemia","bool":false},{"option":"Peritonitis","bool":false},{"option":"Vagal inhibition","bool":true}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"All following statements about renal stones are incorrect except?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperparathyroidism is found in 50 per cent of those presenting with radio-opaque calculi","bool":false},{"option":"Pure uric acid stones are radio-lucent","bool":true},{"option":"A staghorn calculus is composed of calcium-uric acid-magnesium phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"The common bacteria found as a nidus for urinary stones are Streptococci and Pseudomonas","bool":false},{"option":"If a parathyroid adenoma is found to be the cause of renal calculi, it should not be removed before treatment of the calculus","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Resection of an abdominal mass discovered incidentally in a 10-month-old infant by his mother reveals a 10.5 cm well-circumscribed right renal tumor, which is soft in consistency. On slicing, the tumor a pale gray solid surface is noted with cystic areas, necrosis, and hemorrhage. Microscopically, the tumor is composed of blastemal, stromal, and epithelial tissues. Which of the following is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Papillary adenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Neuroblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Wilms tumor","bool":true},{"option":"Oncocytoma","bool":false},{"option":"Renal cell carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the most common presentation of renal cell carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Weight loss","bool":false},{"option":"Costovertebral pain","bool":false},{"option":"Burning micturition","bool":false},{"option":"Palpable mass","bool":false},{"option":"Painless hematuria","bool":true}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the most common site of metastasis for renal cell carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Colon","bool":false},{"option":"Heart","bool":false},{"option":"Breast","bool":false},{"option":"Bone","bool":false},{"option":"Lungs","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Sacher Masoch was an Australian novelist. In his novels, he described characters who obtain sexual gratification when they receive a painful stimulus. This type of sexual perversion is called:","answers":[{"option":"Masochism","bool":true},{"option":"Sadism","bool":false},{"option":"Fetichism","bool":false},{"option":"Eonism","bool":false},{"option":"Uranism","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 67-year-old male who is a known case of chronic renal failure (CRF) comes for his follow-up visit to the nephrologist. His creatinine is stable, however, his bicarbonate is 15 mEq/L. In order to prevent metabolic bone disease, his serum bicarbonate levels should be maintained at what level?","answers":[{"option":"> 25 mEq","bool":false},{"option":"<40 others","bool":false},{"option":"< 21 mEq","bool":false},{"option":"> 21 mEq","bool":true},{"option":"< 10 mEq","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the most common causative organism for acute pyelonephritis?","answers":[{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":true},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeroginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobacter","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"An ultrasound scan of a pregnant woman revealed a large bladder in a fetus (mega cystitis). It is also associated with dilation of the renal pelvis. What is the embryological basis of this anomaly?","answers":[{"option":"Mesonephros","bool":false},{"option":"Ureteric bud","bool":true},{"option":"Pronephros","bool":false},{"option":"Metanephros","bool":false},{"option":"Urogenital sinus","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 50-year-old farmer has 8 children and his youngest son has been sick for the last 3 years and needs surgical intervention for complete recovery. He is already under debt of Rs. 100,000. He decides to sell his kidney to support his son and family. Considering the Islamic perspective on organ transplant, should he be allowed to sell a kidney for transplantation?","answers":[{"option":"Islam allows the sale of organs","bool":false},{"option":"Debates undergoing in Islam","bool":false},{"option":"Islam only allowed to use after permission from scholars","bool":false},{"option":"No such rule in Islam","bool":false},{"option":"Islam prohibits the selling of an organ","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 30-year-old unmarried woman came to a doctor and requested her to induce an abortion. The doctor refused and told the women there is severe punishment for criminal abortion in Pakistan. What is the punishment of criminal abortion before babies' organs are formed in Pakistan?","answers":[{"option":"7 years imprisonment","bool":false},{"option":"3 years imprisonment if with consent","bool":true},{"option":"3 years imprisonment if without consent","bool":false},{"option":"Full diyat of the child","bool":false},{"option":"1/20 diyat of the child","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is true regarding bridegroom impotency?","answers":[{"option":"Seen in men who marry late","bool":false},{"option":"It is temporary in nature","bool":true},{"option":"Seen in alcoholics","bool":false},{"option":"Commonly seen in diabetics","bool":false},{"option":"Due to fear of vaginismus","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A fetus wrapped in an old newspaper was found in the garbage, brought by police to the medico-legal section for age determination. Haase's rule states what?","answers":[{"option":"Square root of crown-heel length in cm gives age of fetus in 1st five months","bool":true},{"option":"Crown Rump length of the fetus in cms gives age in months in 1st five month","bool":false},{"option":"Crown heel length of the fetus in inches gives age in months in 1st five months","bool":false},{"option":"Square root of crown rump length in cm gives age of fetus in 1st five months","bool":false},{"option":"Crown rump length of fetus in inches gives age in months in 1st five months","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 45-year-old patient is admitted to the hospital due to a fracture of the tibia in a roadside accident. During operation a catheter was passed, such patients are prone to urinary tract infections. Which is the commonest causative agent in such a case?","answers":[{"option":"Klebsiella species","bool":false},{"option":"S. saprophyticus","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus species","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"E. coli","bool":true}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A child of 5 years was brought to ED, with multiple bruises of different ages the child is a case of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Act of omission by parents","bool":false},{"option":"Culpable homicide not amounting to murder","bool":false},{"option":"Accidental injuries","bool":false},{"option":"Battered baby syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Sudden infant death syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Filicide is defined by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Killing of a disabled new born child","bool":false},{"option":"Synonymous with criminal abortion","bool":false},{"option":"Killing of viable fetus inside the uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Killing of an illegitimate child","bool":false},{"option":"Killing of a new born child by the parents","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Two boys living in a hostel were caught involved in a homosexual relationship. According to the Pakistan Penal Code (PPC) both of them if proven guilty will be liable to punishment under section?","answers":[{"option":"294","bool":false},{"option":"377","bool":true},{"option":"295","bool":false},{"option":"376","bool":false},{"option":"375","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 62-year-old man presents with a history of smoky urine for the last one week. On examination, there are no positive findings. A urine examination shows pH 5.5, 2+ blood, no protein, and no glucose. Urine cytology reveals atypical cells. Cystoscopy is normal. He has a 60 pack-year history of cigarette smoking. Which of the following is the most likely possibility in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma of penis","bool":false},{"option":"Nodular glomerulosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma of prostate","bool":false},{"option":"Urothelial carcinoma of renal pelvis","bool":true},{"option":"Acute interstitial nephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Before a transplant, the renal transplant team visits the patient to take consent about the procedure and also from the family after counseling. For valid consent, the patient should be which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Mature","bool":true},{"option":"Competent","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomous","bool":false},{"option":"Confident","bool":false},{"option":"Social","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 7-year-old girl presents with puffiness around her eyes. Examination shows a blood pressure of 100/60 mmHg. Laboratory investigations show serum creatinine and urea nitrogen are within normal ranges. Urinalysis shows 4+ proteinuria, no blood, glucose, or ketones. The 24-hour urine protein content of 3.9g. The child's condition improves after a course of corticosteroid therapy. Which of the following is the best option to describe her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome due to minimal change disease","bool":true},{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome due to membranoproliferative glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic renal failure due to dense deposit disease","bool":false},{"option":"Nephritic syndrome due to post-infectious glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome caused by cresentric glomerulonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 20-year-old man is brought into the emergency room after a morphine overdose.  Upon examination, he is unconscious, pupils are pinpoint and non-reactive. Several injection marks are seen on his arms. What is the immediate treatment after maintaining the airway, breathing, and circulation?","answers":[{"option":"Gastric lavage","bool":false},{"option":"Naloxone","bool":true},{"option":"Naloxone with pethidine","bool":false},{"option":"Gastric lavage with tannic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Naloxone with gastric lavage","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following conditions does not favor the development of \"maceration\" in a dead fetus inside the uterine cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Dead fetus remains inside uterus for at least 24 hours","bool":false},{"option":"Membranes ruptured","bool":true},{"option":"Membranes intact","bool":false},{"option":"Dead fetus is surrounded by liqor amni","bool":false},{"option":"Fetus dies in uterus","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the most common complication of a child with nephrotic syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Protein malnutrition","bool":false},{"option":"Deep vein thrombosis","bool":false},{"option":"Infections","bool":true},{"option":"Renal vein thrombosis","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D deficiency","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Hospital waste can be classified into various types. Among the following which one is classified as pathological waste?","answers":[{"option":"Waste from infected animals","bool":false},{"option":"Waste from infected patients","bool":false},{"option":"Organs","bool":true},{"option":"Waste from surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Cultures from laboratory work","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"During the first three months, what is the best-skilled method of termination of pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Vaccum aspiration","bool":true},{"option":"Abortion stick","bool":false},{"option":"Electricity","bool":false},{"option":"Prostaglandins","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"30-year-old Arshad is dependent on morphine as it makes him feel good and also reports that it makes him feel light and relaxed. What are the properties of opium and its derivatives for which they are potentially used as drugs of abuse?","answers":[{"option":"Analgesia","bool":false},{"option":"Narcosis","bool":false},{"option":"Analgesia and narcosis","bool":true},{"option":"Analgesia and sedation","bool":false},{"option":"Sedative","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 22-year-old woman presents with swelling of the legs. On urinalysis, there was increased proteinuria. She is diagnosed to have tubulointerstitial nephritis. It could have been drug-induced. It is characterized by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Appearance of symptoms after about two weeks of exposure","bool":true},{"option":"Dose dependent severity of the disease","bool":false},{"option":"Increased urinary sugar level","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased blood urea nitrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Increased glomerular filtration rate and oliguria","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Whosoever causes a woman with child, whose organs have been formed to miscarry, without good faith for the purpose of saving the life of the woman is known as what?","answers":[{"option":"Shajjah-i-hashimiah","bool":false},{"option":"Shajjah-i-damighah","bool":false},{"option":"Isqat-e-haml","bool":false},{"option":"Isqat-e-janin","bool":true},{"option":"Shajjah-i-ammah","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Pyelonephritis is encountered frequently in clinical settings. Gram-negative organisms are frequently implicated. What is the most common causative organism?","answers":[{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":true},{"option":"Klebsiella","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobacter","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH) is an extremely common cause of prostatic enlargement resulting from the proliferation of stromal and glandular elements. The enlargement of the prostate in men with BPH is an important cause of urinary obstruction. Which zone is commonly involved in benign prostatic hyperplasia?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior","bool":false},{"option":"Central","bool":false},{"option":"Transitional","bool":true},{"option":"Fibromuscular","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A post mortem examination was conducted on a 38-year-old parous woman to see the signs of remote delivery, what are the findings that would confirm the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"The top of fundus is at a lower level than that of broad ligament","bool":false},{"option":"The walls of a uterus are concave from inside forming a wider and rounded cavity","bool":true},{"option":"The external os is vertical irregular and admit 2 fingers","bool":false},{"option":"The internal os is soft, patulous, rounded with a dimple in the center","bool":false},{"option":"The cervix and body of uterus are about the same length","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 30-year-old man is brought into the emergency room after he overdosed on an unknown drug. On examination, his pupils are constricted, nonreactive to light, his breathing is sighing and irregular in pattern, his body is profusely sweating. Based on these findings, what has he overdosed on?","answers":[{"option":"Naloxone","bool":false},{"option":"Milk of magnesia","bool":false},{"option":"Morphine","bool":true},{"option":"Naphthalene","bool":false},{"option":"Kerosene oil","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Spalding sign is a characteristic finding of which of the following condition?","answers":[{"option":"Sodomy","bool":false},{"option":"Unborn baby in the uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Maceration","bool":false},{"option":"Intrauterine dead fetus","bool":true},{"option":"Abortion","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 5-year-old child was brought to the emergency department with complaints of abdominal pain and \r\n hematuria. Upon examination, the child had a flank palpable mass. What is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Renal cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Renal cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Renal access","bool":false},{"option":"Wilms tumor","bool":true},{"option":"Hydronephrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following conditions present with painless gross hematuria?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrolithiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Wilms tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Transitional cell carcinoma of bladder","bool":true},{"option":"Nephroblastoma","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is the characteristic difference between a false virgin and a true virgin?","answers":[{"option":"Funnel shaped vagina","bool":false},{"option":"Hymen edges undulated plus 2 fingers inserted","bool":true},{"option":"Wide vaginal wall","bool":false},{"option":"Non rugosity of vaginal wall","bool":false},{"option":"Narrow vagina","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 41-year-old has had recurrent urinary tract infections for 15 years. On many of these occasions, Proteus mirabilis was cultured from his urine. For the past 4 days, he has had burning pain while urinating, and urinary frequency. On examination, his temperature is 37.9°C, pulse is 70/min, and blood pressure is 135/85 mmHg. There is marked tenderness on deep pressure over the right costovertebral angle and on deep abdominal palpation. Urinalysis shows a pH of 7.5, specific gravity 1.020, 1+ hematuria, and no protein, glucose, or ketones. Microscopic examination of the urine shows many RBCs, WBCs, and triple phosphate crystals. Which of the following renal lesions is most likely to be present?","answers":[{"option":"Renal cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Papillary necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Malignant nephrosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute tubular necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Staghorn calculus","bool":true}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 10-year-old male presents with palpable purpura in the lower extremities and buttocks area. Investigations reveal a decreased glomerular filtration rate (GFR) with a nephritic picture. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Henoch-Schönlein purpura","bool":true},{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":false},{"option":"Focal segmental glomerulosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Post streptococcal glomerulonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 12-year-old boy was being investigated for a kidney tumor. The doctor found no tumor but a unilateral multicystic kidney was found. Which of the following is true about his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Usually bilateral","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital malformation of the renal parenchyma","bool":true},{"option":"Most common genetic cause of ESRD in chidren","bool":false},{"option":"It is inherited","bool":false},{"option":"Ureteric bud does not develop","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 23-year-old man died and the cause of death was found to be a berry aneurysm. On autopsy, multiple, enlarged cystic kidneys were found. Which of the following is true for the deceased's condition?","answers":[{"option":"Leads to hypotension","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital malformation of the renal parenchyma","bool":false},{"option":"Due to mutation in the APKD1 or APKD2 gene","bool":true},{"option":"Usually unilateral","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive form usually presents in young adults","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 26-year-old woman who has been sexually active for 5 years gave birth to a baby 3 years ago. Upon per vaginal examination, what is the finding?","answers":[{"option":"Carunculae myrtiformes","bool":true},{"option":"Caruncla hymenalis","bool":false},{"option":"Raw red vagina","bool":false},{"option":"Papules","bool":false},{"option":"Pustules","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"'Stretch marks' seen in pregnancy are termed as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Linea nigra","bool":false},{"option":"Linea albicans","bool":false},{"option":"Stria gravidarum","bool":true},{"option":"Linea alba","bool":false},{"option":"Pustules","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 45-year-old male presents to the clinic with a case of renal stones. He also has a long-term history of gout and diabetes. Which of the following renal stones are most likely formed in his case?","answers":[{"option":"Calcium phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":true},{"option":"Ammonium magnesium phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium oxalate","bool":false},{"option":"Cystine","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A person was prescribed spironolactone for his treatment. which of the following side effects should the patient be warned about?","answers":[{"option":"Amastia","bool":false},{"option":"Gynecomastia","bool":true},{"option":"Polythelia","bool":false},{"option":"Orchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Polymastia","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is the surest sign of recent delivery?","answers":[{"option":"Linea albicantes","bool":false},{"option":"Absent virginity","bool":false},{"option":"External os rounded","bool":false},{"option":"Striae gravidarum","bool":false},{"option":"External os transverse","bool":true}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A female claims that her husband is impotent and they have never had sexual intercourse. If the clinical examination of this female is carried out, which of the following findings will be certainly present?","answers":[{"option":"Torn fourchette","bool":false},{"option":"Wrinkled labia majora","bool":false},{"option":"Imperforate hymen","bool":false},{"option":"Intact hymen","bool":true},{"option":"Fimbriated hymen","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is a term for the discharge from the vagina immediately after delivery?","answers":[{"option":"Lochia","bool":false},{"option":"Lochia rubra","bool":true},{"option":"Lochia serosa","bool":false},{"option":"Period blood","bool":false},{"option":"Lochia alba","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Regarding childhood type of polycystic kidney disease, which of the following statements is true?","answers":[{"option":"It usually presents unilaterally","bool":false},{"option":"It is non-inherited","bool":false},{"option":"Associated with congenital hepatic fibrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Single cyst is present","bool":false},{"option":"It usually manifests in the renal parenchyma","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 62-year-old man comes into the clinic with complaints of fever, hematuria, and hemoptysis. Renal biopsy reveals linear deposition of IgG and complement (C3) along the basement membrane. What is the most likely diagnosis for his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Berger disease","bool":false},{"option":"Rapidly proliferative glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse proliferative glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Goodpasture syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Renal failure","bool":false},{"option":"Churg-Strauss syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following usually does not cause acute bacterial prostatitis?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus epidermidis","bool":true},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobacter species","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 28-year-old woman, in her third month of pregnancy, came to the clinic with complaints of raised bumps around her areola. What are these bumps called?","answers":[{"option":"Montgomery tubercles","bool":true},{"option":"Striae gravidarum","bool":false},{"option":"Linea albicans","bool":false},{"option":"Linea nigra","bool":false},{"option":"Pustules","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of these measures of central tendency is most affected with extremes of data or outliers?","answers":[{"option":"Mode","bool":false},{"option":"Median","bool":false},{"option":"Percentile","bool":false},{"option":"Mean","bool":true},{"option":"Range","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which type of statistical test is commonly used if the sample size is below 30, to determine whether the mean of a population significantly differs from a specific value or from the mean of another population and to determine whether the difference is statistically significant?","answers":[{"option":"Anova","bool":false},{"option":"Logistic regression","bool":false},{"option":"Linear regression","bool":false},{"option":"Chi square","bool":false},{"option":"T test","bool":true}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 20-year-old male presents with a history of an upper respiratory infection followed by gross hematuria, 1 day later. Urine D/R shows increased RBCs, RBC casts, and proteinuria. His renal function test shows increased creatinine. Renal biopsy shows IgA deposition in the mesangium. What would be the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Anti-GBM disease (Goodpasture syndrome)","bool":false},{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":false},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":true},{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous nephopathy","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 10-year-old male is brought to the clinic by his parents with complaints of periorbital puffiness and pedal edema. His urine analysis shows proteinuria, absence of RBCs and casts. You suspect minimal change disease. What would the renal biopsy findings in this patient be?","answers":[{"option":"Dense deposits on subepithelial surface of basement membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Sclerosis of segments of some glomeruli","bool":false},{"option":"Crescent formation","bool":false},{"option":"Increased IgA deposition in mesangium","bool":false},{"option":"Normal light microscopy and immunofluorescence","bool":true}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 62-year-old woman is diagnosed with hypercalcemia related to a parathyroid hormone-secreting tumor. Other than cancer chemotherapy, which of the following diuretics agents would help treat her hypercalcemia?","answers":[{"option":"Furosemide","bool":true},{"option":"Hydrochlorothiazide","bool":false},{"option":"Acetazolamide","bool":false},{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":false},{"option":"Mannitol","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following drug that acts on the proximal tubule has relatively low efficacy in blocking the reabsorption of sodium (Na), but is useful in the treatment of glaucoma and as a prophylactic to prevent acute mountain sickness?","answers":[{"option":"Furosemide","bool":false},{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":false},{"option":"Metolazone","bool":false},{"option":"Acetazolamide","bool":true},{"option":"Amiloride","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 60-year-old male presented with complaints of anuria. He was investigated and diagnosed with prostatic carcinoma. Imaging studies show dilatation of the renal pelvis. A cut section of the kidney shows a dilated pelvis and calyces, as well as thinning of the renal parenchyma. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral hydronephrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Renal vein thrombosis","bool":false},{"option":"Malignant nephrosclerosis","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 34-year-old man is awakened at night because of severe lower abdominal pain that radiates to the groin. The pain is very intense and comes in waves. The next morning, he notices blood in his urine. He has no underlying illnesses and has been healthy all his life. Urinalysis shows a pH of 7; specific gravity of 1.020; and no protein, glucose, ketones, or nitrite. The patient is advised to drink more water. He likes iced tea and consumes large quantities over the course of a hot summer. He continues to have similar episodes. Which of the following substances is most likely to be increased in his urine?","answers":[{"option":"Cystine","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium oxalate","bool":true},{"option":"Mucoprotein","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium ammonium phosphate","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is not a cause of unilateral hydronephrosis?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Calculus in renal pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"BPH & carcinoma of prostate","bool":true},{"option":"Tumor of ureter","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital pelviureteric junction obstruction","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 69-year-old man comes to the hospital with end-stage renal failure. He gives a history of analgesic use for arthritis and occasional social alcohol use. He reports that 20 years ago he was told by a doctor that some of his blood tests related to his kidneys were abnormal and was advised to attend hospital for follow up. However, he felt fine so he went to live in his village and did not attend hospital until now. Ultrasound of his kidneys shows markedly enlarged kidneys bilaterally with multiple cysts. Which of the following is correct regarding the pathogenesis of this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Most likely due to chemicals and toxins in the water at his village","bool":false},{"option":"Inheritance plays no role","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohol related","bool":false},{"option":"Primary ciliopathy implicated","bool":true},{"option":"Caused by non-steroidal anti-inflammatory medication","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"An 85-year-old male is diagnosed with renal cell carcinoma. Regarding this, all of the following statements are true except?","answers":[{"option":"It is more common in men","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound and tri-phasic CT urography are imaging methods of choice","bool":false},{"option":"In 25 percent of cases, there are no local symptoms","bool":false},{"option":"A left sided varicocele may be a presenting feature in males","bool":false},{"option":"Following radical nephrectomy, radiotherapy should be given","bool":true}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 45-year-old lady is booked for a cholecystectomy. During her preoperative workup, radiological investigations reveal multiple cystic dilations of the collecting ducts in the renal medulla. No cortical scarring is present and renal function is normal. What is the most likely cause of these findings?","answers":[{"option":"Tubulo-interstitial nephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Medullary sponge kidney","bool":true},{"option":"Adult polycystic kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Childhood polycystic kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Nephronophthisis","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 6-year-old child undergoes surgical exploration and nephrectomy for a suspected kidney tumor. His ultrasound shows an enlarged multicystic, irregular left kidney. Biopsy shows no tumor. However, there are islands of undifferentiated mesenchyme and cartilage. Which of the following is correct regarding this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Commonest genetic cause of end stage renal disease in children","bool":false},{"option":"It is rarely associated with other lower urinary tract anomalies","bool":false},{"option":"Primary ciliopathy implicated","bool":false},{"option":"Excellent prognosis after nephrectomy","bool":true},{"option":"Inherited disorder","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 70-year-old man, with a history of smoking, complains of hematuria associated with pain in his left loin. He passes clots that are 'worm-like' according to him. On examination, he has an enlarged left kidney with left scrotal swelling. What is the investigation of choice?","answers":[{"option":"CT KUB","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Urine DR and CS","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound scrotum","bool":false},{"option":"Triphasic CT urography","bool":true}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 55-year-old male patient complains of incontinence and lower urinary tract symptoms, predominantly voiding symptoms, for the last several months. On examination, he has suprapubic tenderness. Urine examination shows red blood cells and growth of Proteus and staphylococci. All of these are voiding symptoms except?","answers":[{"option":"Incontinence","bool":true},{"option":"Straining","bool":false},{"option":"Poor flow","bool":false},{"option":"Hesitancy","bool":false},{"option":"Intermittency","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"An 82-year-old man passed away in the hospital. He had a history of frequent urinary problems. His body underwent a medical autopsy. The report mentions \"scarring of both kidneys\". What might this be a feature of?","answers":[{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":false},{"option":"Acute pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic pyelonephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A patient on acetaminophen developed renal symptoms and was diagnosed with drug-induced acute kidney injury. Acute kidney injury can result from exposure to toxins or ischemia. What is it characterized by?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased glomerular filtration rate and oliguria","bool":true},{"option":"Increased urinary sugar level","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased urinary creatinine","bool":false},{"option":"Increased glomerular filtration rate and oliguria","bool":false},{"option":"Increased glomerular filtration rate and increased urinary creatinine","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 70-year-old male patient complains of dysuria and lower urinary tract symptoms for several years. On examination, he has suprapubic tenderness. Ultrasound revealed a 60gm enlarged prostate and a 2 cm bladder stone. Which of the following statements is false?","answers":[{"option":"A uric acid calculus is radio-lucent","bool":false},{"option":"An oxalate calculus develops in sterile urine","bool":false},{"option":"In men, an enlarged prostate and stones can be dealt with at the same time","bool":false},{"option":"Open surgery is indicated due to concomitant bladder stone","bool":true},{"option":"Most bladder stones can be treated by minimal access surgery","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 45-year-old male, a recent visitor from Sudan, comes to the emergency with painless hematuria at the end of micturition. Clinical examination reveals no abnormality. On cystoscopy, he is found to have scattered tubercles and islands of pale patches resembling sand. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Bladder carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis of bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Schistosomiasis","bool":true},{"option":"Bladder stone","bool":false},{"option":"Bladder diverticulum","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 25 year-old-male presents with a reduced urinary output. He has a history of gouty arthritis for which he has taken indomethacin. Investigations reveal a Cr=2.5 mg/dl, and urine D/R shows WBC casts. What is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Acute interstitial nephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous glomerulopathy","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A middle-aged male presented to the outpatient department with complaints of epistaxis, hemoptysis and dark colored urine. Which of the following is the most likely condition?","answers":[{"option":"P-ANCA associated vasculities","bool":false},{"option":"Cryoglobulinemia","bool":false},{"option":"Nephritic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Wegener's disease","bool":true},{"option":"Goodpasture syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"In acute kidney injury, what contributes to metabolic acidosis?","answers":[{"option":"Excess sodium conservation by renal tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Renal tubules inability to generate bicarbonate","bool":true},{"option":"Too few hydrogen ions, which increases the blood pH","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium movement from extracellular to intracellular fluid","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following cannot cause acute kidney injury?","answers":[{"option":"Renal calculi","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic ketoacidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Nephrocalcinosis","bool":false},{"option":"Dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"Heart failure","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is least likely to be filtered from glomerular capillaries?","answers":[{"option":"Potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Albumin","bool":true},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Inulin","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the colloidal osmotic pressure in Bowman's capsule?","answers":[{"option":"18 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"less than 1 mmHg","bool":true},{"option":"10 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"60 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"32 mmHg","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A glaucoma patient was prescribed acetazolamide. Which of the following describes its mechanism of action?","answers":[{"option":"Potentiation of carbonic anhydrase in all parts of the body","bool":false},{"option":"Reduction of reabsorption of bicarbonates","bool":true},{"option":"Increased excretion of bicarbonate in the aqueous humor","bool":false},{"option":"Increased uptake of sodium in proximal tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Increased excretion of hydrogen","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 70-year-old woman is admitted for a fainting spell with no history of trauma. Blood pressure is 110/60 (lying down) and 60/40 (sitting). Recently, she was prescribed diuretics for cardiac problems. Which of the following drugs might be responsible for her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrochlorothiazide","bool":false},{"option":"Amiloride","bool":false},{"option":"Acetazolamide","bool":false},{"option":"Furosemide","bool":true},{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of urinary tract infections in females?","answers":[{"option":"Sexually transmitted diseases","bool":false},{"option":"Anatomical predisposition","bool":true},{"option":"Eating contaminated food","bool":false},{"option":"Use of antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Unhygienic conditions","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"The kidneys lie at which level?","answers":[{"option":"T12-L3","bool":true},{"option":"T12-L1","bool":false},{"option":"T12-L4","bool":false},{"option":"T12-L2","bool":false},{"option":"T11-L3","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is considered the gold standard for the treatment of benign prostate hyperplasia (BPH)?","answers":[{"option":"Tadalafil","bool":false},{"option":"5-alpha reductase inhibitors","bool":false},{"option":"Combination drug therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Transurethral resection of prostate (TURP)","bool":true},{"option":"Alpha blockers","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Rapid correction of hyponatremia may cause which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebral edema","bool":false},{"option":"Central pontine myelinolysis","bool":true},{"option":"Brain herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Heart attack","bool":false},{"option":"Stroke","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most common organism responsible for causing nephritic syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella","bool":false},{"option":"Beta hemolytic streptococci","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following methods is not used to reduce viability of microorganisms?","answers":[{"option":"Antisepsis","bool":false},{"option":"Disinfection","bool":false},{"option":"Incineration","bool":true},{"option":"Sterilization","bool":false},{"option":"Sanitization","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following drugs inhibits aldosterone in the distal tubule?","answers":[{"option":"Benzthiazide","bool":false},{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":true},{"option":"Metolazone","bool":false},{"option":"Triamterene","bool":false},{"option":"Acetazolamide","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is the site of action of mannitol?","answers":[{"option":"Ascending loop of henle","bool":false},{"option":"Descending loop of henle","bool":false},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting duct","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":true}]},{"id":95,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Sexual enjoyment from inflicting pain on others as well as on oneself is called which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Satyriasis","bool":false},{"option":"Algolagnia","bool":true},{"option":"Masochism","bool":false},{"option":"Sadism","bool":false},{"option":"Beastiality","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"A girl had calcium oxalate stones which were recently removed and treated. Which of the following drugs should she now avoid to prevent the formation of stones?","answers":[{"option":"Mannitol","bool":false},{"option":"Amiloride","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrothiazide","bool":false},{"option":"Spirinolactone","bool":false},{"option":"Furosemide","bool":true}]},{"id":97,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is the initial investigation in a patient with suspected ureteric calculi?","answers":[{"option":"CT scan","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Cystoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous urography","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray KUB","bool":true}]},{"id":98,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"According to World Health Organization (WHO), drug dependence is defined as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Intoxication with harmful effects on himself","bool":false},{"option":"Desire to take drug repeatedly and increase the doses","bool":true},{"option":"Intoxication with harmful effects on society","bool":false},{"option":"No withdrawal symptoms","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic and periodic intoxication with harmful effects on himself and society","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"At which of the following sites does triamterene act on?","answers":[{"option":"Glomerulus","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting duct","bool":true}]},{"id":100,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2021","question":"An 85-year-old male presented with renal cell carcinoma. Which of the following is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"Ultrasound and triphasic CT urography are the imaging methods of choice","bool":false},{"option":"Following radical nephrectomy, radiotherapy should be given","bool":true},{"option":"A left sided varicocele may be a presenting feature in a male","bool":false},{"option":"In 25% of patients there are no local symptoms","bool":false},{"option":"It occurs more commonly in men","bool":false}]}]
export default arr